YANG, YI

canna1102.yy@gmail.com

+852-53094947

vangyiathk.com

Summary

I am passionate at innovative data visualization. As a researcher, I use visual analytics approach to uncover interesting trends and relationships from data. As an engineer, I build up interactive visualization systems with modern front-end techniques to help analysts deal with massive data.

Work Experience

Researcher - Lenovo Big Data Lab

Apr. 2016 - Present

- Take responsibilities of front-end engineering, including architecture design, development, building and deployment.
- Retrieve, process and prepare data from various sources such as database, REST APIs and web scraping.
- Work closely with data scientists to perform exploratory data analysis with visualization software and libraries.
- Create prototype tools to demonstrate ideas and expose insights.

Project Experience

Various Geographic Data Visualizations for Knowledge Discovery

Feb. 2016 - Present

- Visualize thousands of taxis one day in Shenzhen using their GPS trajectory data to discover spatio-temporal traffic patterns.
- Develop a traffic inspecting tool to visually compare actual vehicle movements with its effect on road speed.
- Identify migrant origins in China based on the dynamic locations of mobile users and visualize the prevailing migration patterns.
- Use a combination of SVG, HTML5 canvas and WebGL techniques to improve the quality of front-end performance.

Graph Visualization and Analysis Software

Jun. 2016 - Present

- Collaborate with project owner to conduct competing product research and product orientation decision.
- Take a lead role in developing front-end web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and AngularJS.
- Establish core functional components for data searching, visualization and management.
- Build prototype of user interfaces based on internal requirements and customer feedback.

Alibaba Tianchi Aviation Big Data Competition

Nov. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- Design and develop a large screen visualization to help analyze and optimize airport gate assignment visually.
- Win best visualization award.

Alibaba Tianchi Big Data Visualization Competition

Jul. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- Propose a visual analytics solution that displays and explores logistics data in the scenario of last-mile delivery.
- Win honorable mention award and participate in a road show at headquarter of Alibaba in hangzhou.

Visual Analytics System for Making Sense of Large Document Collections

Jun. 2015 - Feb. 2016

- Survey about topic modeling methods for large document collection analysis.
- Propose *VISTopic*, a visual analytics system designed for hierarchical topic modeling, to assist end users exploring and understanding document collections.
- Discover topic taxonomy, trend and representative authors in the field of IEEE VIS by analyzing its publications in 25 years.
- Publish research results on an academic journal Journal of Visual Informatics, 2017 as first author.

Education Experience

Sep. 2013 - Mar. 2016

Master of Philosophy - Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

- Supervised by professor Huamin QU in Department of Computer Science and Engineering
- Cumulative Grade Average 3.5/4.0
- HKUST postgraduate scholarship owner

Sep. 2009 - Jun. 2013

Bachelor of Science - Nanjing University

- Department of Electronic and Information Science, GPA3.7/4.0
- Second-class and third-class of the People's Scholarship